A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor Andrew J. Montague, 1884-1907 (bulk 1902-1905)
Library of Virginia
- Series II: Correspondence (Alphabetical), 1884-1907 (bulk 1902-1905)., Extent: 8 boxes. (Box 16-22a)
  The most significant material in this series relates to the Capitol Enlargement. The Capitol Enlargement files contain correspondence, bills, receipts, minutes, acts, and reports. The correspondence includes letters to the governor from contractors, manufacturers, etc. There is correspondence from Samuel W. Bigger, Clerk of the Legislative Committee of Restoring & Repairing the State Capitol Building regarding payment of expenses for attending meetings of the Commission, payments for contracts, and applications for the position of Engineer in charge of the proposed improvements. W.A. Chesterman, General Contractor, writes regarding progress in the improvements to the Capitol Building, sub-contractors for brickwork, roofing, painting, etc., and his contract as contractor. D.Q. Eggleston, Secretary of the Commonwealth, writes regarding furniture needed in his new office in the new Capitol Building. E.A. Morgan, Acting Superintendent of the Penitentiary, writes regarding convicts from the Penitentiary for digging the foundation & grading. The architectural firm of Noland & Baskervill enclose bids for work on the Capitol. John Keevan Peebles writes regarding drawings of his work as architect of the Capitol Enlargement. John W. Richardson, Register & Superintendent of the Land Office, writes regarding coal contracts, phones for the Capitol, windows, fireproofing, furniture, his office, carpeting, and radiators. Sydnor & Hundley, Inc., provide pencil sketches of furniture for the Capitol. In addition to correspondence, there are various proposals submitted for furnishing the House & Senate, providing labor & material to do the work according to the plans & specifications in the alterations & additions. Lastly, there is a blueprint drawing of a water cooler & stand and double lockers ("W" folder).
  Applications for pardon, bills and receipts, outgoing telegrams, quarterly reports, recommendations, text books, and Thanksgiving proclamations comprise a significant portion of this series. The applications for pardon are filed alphabetically and contain petitions, correspondence, prison records, & court records. The bills & receipts are also filed alphabetically and relate to expenses of the Executive Mansion. In addition, there is a separate folder regarding expenses for the funeral of Fitzhugh Lee. Outgoing telegrams from Governor Montague to various individuals relate to requisitions, judges, special elections, regrets, lynchings, fugitives, rewards, and commutations. The quarterly reports originate from the Central State Hospital and Southwestern State Hospital, along with the Newport News Quarantine Office. Quarterly reports can also be found in the Correspondence (Chronological) Series. The recommendations by Governor Montague concern positions on the Board of Fisheries, judgeships in the Chesterfield Court & Twentieth Circuit, Quarantine Officers, & the Superintendent of Public Printing. The Text Book files include correspondence from book companies furnishing text books for Virginia schools. These files sometimes include chapters, synopses, & excerpts of text books. Finally, the Thanksgiving proclamations are simply proclamations to hold a day of feasting and prayer from the governors of other states & territories.
  Of note is a census taken of the four wards of the City of Manchester, Virginia, on 4 May 1903. The census is housed in two volumes (in one box) and contain names and notes race, gender, and marriage status of each person. An Act of the General Assembly of Virginia Extra Session of 1902-1904 (p. 82, Chapt. 88) was passed 13 March 1903 approving a census to be drawn as the General Assembly believed that that last census did not fully count the inhabitants of the City of Manchester. [These volumes were found at a later date and added to the collection in 2024.]
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Annual Report of the State Library Board, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Applications for Pardon
    - B-F, 1902-1907 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - G-P, 1902-1906 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - R-T, 1904-1905 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Applications for Reinstatement of Citizenship, 1902-1905 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Bills & Receipts
    - A, 1902-1904 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - B, 1902-1906 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - C, 1902-1905 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - D, 1902-1905 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - E, 1902-1906 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - F, 1902-1905 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - G, 1902-1905 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - H, 1902-1905 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - J, 1904-1905 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - L, 1902-1906 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Lee, Fitzhugh (Funeral), 1905 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - M, 1902-1906 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - N, 1902-1903 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - O, 1902 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - P, 1902-1906 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - R, 1902-1905 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - S, 1902-1906 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Southern Bell Telephone & Telegraph Company, 1902-1906 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - T, 1902-1906 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - W, 1902-1906 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Y, 1904 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Capitol Enlargement
    - Act, 1904 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Bills & Receipts
      - A, 1902-1905 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - B, 1904-1906 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - C, 1905-1906 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - E, 1904-1906 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - F, 1905 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - G, 1904-1905 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - H, 1904-1906 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - J, 1904-1905 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - K, 1904-1905 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - M, 1904-1906 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - N, 1904-1905 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - P, 1904-1905 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - R, 1904-1905 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - S, 1904-1906 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - T, 1904-1905 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - W, 1904-1906 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence
      - A, 1902-1905 (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - B, 1902-1905 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - C, 1902-1906 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - D, 1902-1906 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - E, 1902-1905 (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - F, 1902-1904 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - G, 1902-1905 (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - H, 1904-1906 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - J, 1902-1906 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - K, 1904-1905 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - L, 1902-1905 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - M, 1902-1906 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - N, 1902-1906 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - O, 1904-1906 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - P, 1902-1906 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - R, 1902-1906 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - S, 1902-1906 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - T, 1902-1905 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - U, 1906 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - V, 1902-1906 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - W, 1902-1906 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Minutes of the Legislative Commission, 1902-1903 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Report of the Committee on the Enlargement, Restoration, & Repair of the Capitol Building, 1906 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Specifications for Fireproofing & Additions of the Virginia State Capitol, 1904 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Warrants Drawn, 1902-1906 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Congressional Record of Thomas S. Martin, 1895-1905 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - List of Pardons, Commutations, etc., 1902-1906 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing Telegrams
    - A, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - B, 1902-1906 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - C, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - D, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - E, 1902-1906 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - F, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - G, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - H, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - J, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - K, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - L, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - M, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - N, 1903-1906 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - O, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - P, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - R, 1902-1906 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - S, 1902-1906 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - T, 1902-1906 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - V, 1902-1906 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - W, 1902-1905 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Quarterly Reports
    - Central State Hospital, 1902-1904 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Newport News Quarantine Station, 1901-1906 (See Oversized) (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Southwestern State Hospital, 1901-1906 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Recommendations
    - Board of Fisheries
      - Bland, J.L., 1902 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Bowdoin, J.W., 1902 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Bridges, Herbert L., 1901-1902 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Curtis, John A., 1902 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Farinholt, Col. B.L., 1898-1902 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Fletcher, Frank, 1901-1902 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Miller, Seth, 1901-1902 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Pilcher, R.M., 1901-1902 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Richardson, T.J., 1901-1902 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Schultice, Robert W., 1901-1902 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Judgeships
      - Chesterfield Court
        - Moore, T. Verner, 1903 (Box 20, Folder 11)
        - Pool, Lawrence, 1903 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Twentieth Circuit, 1905 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Quarantine Officer
      - Lynch, Dr. J.F., 1901-1902 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Meredith, Dr. W.B., 1901-1902 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Norfleet, Dr. J.B., 1901-1902 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Vance, Charles R., 1901-1904 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Wood, Dr. W.K, 1901-1902 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Superintendent of Public Printing, 1905 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Reports of Clerks of Courts re. Levy for Public Roads, 1905-1906 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Requests for Contributions, 1901-1903 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Text Books
    - A, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - B, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - C, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - E, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - F, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - G, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - H, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - L, 1903-1904 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - M, 1903-1904 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - N, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - R, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - S, 1904 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - T, 1904 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - W, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Thanksgiving Proclamations, 1902-1905 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Virginia's Claim against the United States, 1884-1902 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Census, City of Manchester (Va.), 1903 May 4 (Box 22a)
- Series III. Letter Books, 1901-1906., Extent: 6 boxes. (Box 23-28)
  The Letter Books series is housed in six archival boxes and is arranged chronologically. This series documents outgoing letters by Governor Andrew J. Montague. Correspondence in this series relates to applications for positions, payments, pardons, recommendations, appointments, invitations, regrets, annual passes of transportation companies (prohibited under the new Constitution), resignations, U.S. Senate candidacy against Thomas Martin, Louisiana Purchase Exposition, launching of the battleship "Virginia," and the State Central Committee. Noteworthy correspondents include judges, commonwealth's attorneys, William A. Jones (House of Representatives), clerks of courts, colleges & universities, John S. Patton (University of Virginia), Henry St. George Tucker, and Charles N. Needham (President of the Columbian University in Washington, D.C.). Some of the outgoing letters are from Montague's secretary D.A. Ritchie. These files are arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1901-1902 Dec. 1 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 1902 Dec. 4-1903 July 3 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - 1903 July 3-1904 Mar. 31 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - 1904 Mar. 31-Oct.24 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - 1904 Oct. 24-1905 Feb. 11 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - 1905 Feb. 11-Mar. 11 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - 1905 Feb. 23-Mar. 30 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - 1905 Mar. 13-Apr. 12 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - 1905 Mar. 31-May 6 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - 1905 Apr. 13-May 20 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - 1905 May 9-June 6 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - 1905 June 6-28 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - 1905 June 28-July 25 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - 1905 July 25-Aug. 19 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - 1905 Aug. 18-Dec. 19 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - 1905 Dec. 20-1906 Jan. 31 (Box 28, Folder 2)
- Series IV. Personal Papers, 1895-1906 (bulk 1902-1905)., Extent: 24 boxes. (Box 29-53)
  The Personal Papers series is housed in twenty-four archival boxes and is arranged in two subseries. Subseries have been designated for Chronological Files & Subject Files. This series mainly consists of files transferred from a collection of Montague records donated by Elizabeth Hoskins Montague (Acc. 22001) and transferred from the Library of Virginia's Private Papers Section. Although it's labeled "Personal Papers" much of the series documents the work of Andrew J. Montague in his official capacity as governor of Virginia between 1902 and 1906. The correspondence in this series should be researched in conjunction with the correspondence found in the previous series.
  Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Subseries A: Chronological Files, 1902-1906., 22 boxes.
    The Chronological Files subseries is housed in twenty-one archival boxes and is arranged in chronological order, then alphabetically by correspondent with undated and unsigned files at the end of each year. This subseries contains incoming correspondence sent to Andrew Montague during his four-year term as governor between January 1902 and January 1906. Correspondence in this series relates to applications for positions in state government, invitations, congratulatory letters, news clippings, autograph requests, speaking/appearance requests, acceptances of positions, recommendations, financial assistance, politics, and his candidacy for the U.S. Senate. Note that the reverse of the correspondence provides instructions as to whether the letter is to "ans[wer]" or "file." This subseries includes many significant correspondents including J. Hoge Tyler, Joseph E. Williard (Lieutenant Governor), Carter Glass (U.S. House of Representatives), William A. Jones (U.S. House of Representatives), the Thomas Jefferson Memorial Association of the United States, the Grand Camp of Confederate Veterans, John S. Patton (Chairman of the University of Virginia), the Louisiana Purchase Exposition Commission, Charles W. Needham (President of George Washington University), William A. Anderson (Attorney General), William F. Drewry (Superintendent of Central State Hospital), J. Taylor Ellyson (Chairman of the Virginia State Democratic Committee), Robert W. Hunter (Secretary of Virginia Military Records), Fitzhugh Lee (President of the Jamestown Exposition Company), Thomas Martin (U.S. Senate), W. Nalle (Adjutant General), John Garland Pollard (future governor), William Loeb, Jr. (Secretary to President Woodrow Wilson), Elihu Root (Secretary of War), John D. Rockefeller, President Theodore Roosevelt, and Scott Shipp (Superintendent of the Virginia Military Institute).
    - 1902
      - A (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - B
        - January-June (Box 29, Folder 2)
        - July-December (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - C (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - D (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - E (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - F (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - G (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - H (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - I (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - J (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - K (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - L (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - M
        - January-September (Box 30, Folder 6)
        - October-December (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - N (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - O (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - P (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Q (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - R (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - S
        - January-June (Box 31, Folder 2)
        - July-December (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - T (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - V (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - W (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Y (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Z (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Unsigned or Undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - 1903
      - A (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - B
        - January-June (Box 32, Folder 2)
        - July-December (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - C
        - January-June (Box 32, Folder 4)
        - July-December (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - D (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - E (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - F (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - G (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - H (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - I (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - J (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - K (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - L (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - M
        - January-June (Box 33, Folder 7)
        - July-December (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - N (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - O (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - P (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Q (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - R (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - S
        - January-June (Box 34, Folder 4)
        - July-December (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - T (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - U (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - V (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - W (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - Y (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Z (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - Unsigned or Undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - 1904
      - A (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - B
        - Jan.-June (Box 35, Folder 2)
        - July-Dec. (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - C (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - D (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - E (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - F (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - G (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - H
        - Jan.-June (Box 36, Folder 2)
        - July-Dec. (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - I (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - J (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - K (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - L (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - M
        - Jan.-May (Box 36, Folder 8)
        - June-Dec. (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - N (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - O (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - P (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Q (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - R
        - Jan.-Sept. (Box 37, Folder 6)
        - Oct-Dec. (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - S
        - Jan.-May (Box 37, Folder 8)
        - June-Dec. (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - T (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - U (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - V (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - W
        - Jan.-Aug. (Box 38, Folder 5)
        - Sept.-Dec. (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Y (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Unsigned or Undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - 1905
      - A
        - Jan.-May (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Sept.-Dec. (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - B
        - Jan.-March 20 (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - March 21-April (Box 39, Folder 4)
        - May (Box 39, Folder 5)
        - June-July (Box 40, Folder 1)
        - August (Box 40, Folder 2)
        - Sept.-Dec. (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - C
        - Jan.-Feb. (Box 40, Folder 4)
        - March-April 15 (Box 40, Folder 5)
        - April 16-May (Box 40, Folder 6)
        - June-July 15 (Box 41, Folder 1)
        - July 16-August (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - Sept.-Dec. (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - D
        - Jan.-April (Box 41, Folder 4)
        - May-July (Box 41, Folder 5)
        - Aug.-Dec. (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - E
        - Jan.-May (Box 42, Folder 1)
        - June-Dec. (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - F
        - Jan.-May (Box 42, Folder 3)
        - June-Dec. (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - G
        - Jan.-April (Box 42, Folder 5)
        - May-July (Box 43, Folder 1)
        - Aug.-Dec. (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - H
        - Jan.-Feb. (Box 43, Folder 3)
        - March (Box 43, Folder 4)
        - April (Box 43, Folder 5)
        - May (Box 43, Folder 6)
        - June-July (Box 44, Folder 1)
        - Aug.-Dec. (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - I (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - J
        - Jan.-May (Box 44, Folder 4)
        - June-Dec. (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - K (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - L
        - Jan.-April (Box 45, Folder 1)
        - May-Aug. (Box 45, Folder 2)
        - Sept.-Dec. (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - M
        - Jan.-March 15 (Box 45, Folder 4)
        - March 16-April (Box 45, Folder 5)
        - May (Box 45, Folder 6)
        - June-July (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - Aug.-Sept. (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Oct.-Dec. (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - N (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - O (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - P
        - Jan.-April (Box 46, Folder 6)
        - May-July (Box 46, Folder 7)
        - Aug.-Dec. (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Q (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - R
        - Jan.-April (Box 47, Folder 3)
        - May-July (Box 47, Folder 4)
        - Aug.-Dec. (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - S
        - Jan.-March 15 (Box 47, Folder 6)
        - March 16-April (Box 47, Folder 7)
        - May (Box 48, Folder 1)
        - June-July (Box 48, Folder 2)
        - Aug.-Dec. (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - T
        - Jan.-April (Box 48, Folder 4)
        - May-July (Box 48, Folder 5)
        - Aug.-Dec. (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - U (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - V (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - W
        - Jan.-March 15 (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - March 16-April 15 (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - April 16-May 15 (Box 49, Folder 4)
        - May 16-June (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - July-Aug. (Box 49, Folder 6)
        - Sept.-Dec. (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Y (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Z (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Unsigned or Undated
        - A-Q (Box 50, Folder 1)
        - R-Z (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: Subject Files, 1895-1906., 3 boxes.
    The Subject Files subseries is housed in three archival boxes and is arranged in alphabetical order. This subseries contains correspondence, legislation, news clippings, receipts, telegrams, voter lists, and other sundry items. The campaign material file includes news clippings regarding Montague's failed attempt to win Thomas Martin's seat in the U.S. Senate. In addition, this file contains a few pieces of legislation and other documents related to Martin's record as senator. Similarly, there are numerous lists of Democratic voters arranged by county that were compiled for Montague's campaign. Noteworthy is a published directory for Louisa County in 1905. Especially prevalent in this subseries are files regarding clemency requests for J. Samuel McCue, the former mayor of Charlottesville who was hanged in 1905 for the murder of his wife. These files are arranged alphabetically by correspondent and include petitions, newspaper clippings, and McCue's published petition for a rehearing in the Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia. Telegrams from Montague or D.A. Ritchie, his secretary, are also found in this subseries. These files are arranged alphabetically, then chronologically, and include regrets and acceptances for appearances or speaking engagements, sympathy messages, and others. Lastly, there are receipts for various expenditures kept by Montague a few years before and during his governorship. These receipts document purchases for clothing, household goods, groceries, livery, utilities, memberships, and other items.
    - Campaign Material, 1903-1906 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Lists of Voters
      - Accomack-Buckingham, 1904-1905 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Charlotte-Greene, 1903-1905 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Halifax-Lunenburg, 1905 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Madison-Patrick, 1905 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous, 1905 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Petersburg-Prince William, 1904-1905 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Princess Anne-Warren, 1903-1905 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Warwick-York, 1905 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - McCue Clemency
      - A, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Anonymous, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - B, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - C, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - D, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - E, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - F, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - G, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - H, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - J, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - K, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - L, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - M, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - N, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 14)
      - Newspapers, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 15)
      - O, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - P, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 17)
      - Petition for Rehearing, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 18)
      - Petitions, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 19)
      - R, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 20)
      - S, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 21)
      - T, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 22)
      - V, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 23)